Faizan Arif

New Delhi | Faizanarif.design@gmail.com | (971) 788-4453 | www.faizanarif.in | www.Linkedln.com/faizanarif9

Summary

A UX/UI designer with over 3.5 years of strong experience in designing usable, accessible, and user-centred digital products for mobile and web. Working across publishing, education e-commerce, and web3 industries making complex ideas into simple products for people, companies and governments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Realcoderz, UX/UI Designer

Noida-135, India | Jul 2021-Present

- Designed the entire mobile application user interface using Figma, ensuring an intuitive and user-friendly experience.
- Performed full-stack website launches for clients that specialize in front-end functionality, browser use, and compatibility.
- Created wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity designs to visualize user flows and interactions.

Sleepwell (Contractual), Product Designer

Noida-135, India | Aug 2022-Apr 2024

- Designed product called PM system where you can measure employees performance within the org.
- Designed new mobile app for dealers which have currently 20K+ downloads on Android & ios.
- Contributed to the improvement of design processes and workflows within the team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Design Skill**: User Experience, Wireframing, Prototyping, Visual Design, Interaction Design, Typography, Branding, Usability Testing, Storyboarding, Competitive Analysis, Designing Research
- Programming Skill: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, TailwindCss, React js,
- Designing Tools: Figma, Adobe XD, Dora.run, Spline, Inkscape

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science & Engineering

Greater Noida, India | Jul 2016-May 2020

I.T.S. Engineering College, - 72.8%

Courses: Programming in C,Algorithm Design, Data Structure, Web Programming, Al, ML, Python, OS

Intermediate, Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

UP, India | Jul 2013-May 2015

Children HR. Sec. School, - 84%

High School, Science

UP, India | Jul 2011-May 2013

Children HR. Sec. School, - 83%

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Google UX Design Professional Certificate Course : Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design
- Coursera: Visual Elements of User Interface Design California Institute of the Arts